A Guide to the Military Rule Election Records of the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1867, 1869
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
A Guide to the Military Rule Election Records of the Virginia Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1867, 1869
The Library of Virginia
50706
XX cubic feet (XX boxes)
Commonwealth, Secretary of the
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
No acquisition information available.
Biographical Information
In the summer of 1866, Congress passed the 14th Amendment guaranteeing the rights of freedmen and preventing former Confederate officials from holding office. Virginia, failing to ratify the amendment, was placed under military rule as a result of the passage of the first Reconstruction Act on March 2, 1867. Virginia became Military District No. 1 under the command of Major Gen. John M. Schofield. Under the provisions of the Reconstruction Acts, it was necessary for the states of the old Confederacy to call conventions to draft new state constitutions. As directed, the Commander of the Military District in Virginia registered all male citizens 21 years of age or older and supervised an election held October 22, 1867. This election would determine whether or not Virginia would hold a constitutional convention, and would also elect delegates to the convention, if held. This election was especially significant because it was the first election to include African American participation.
Voters approved the constitutional convention and elected five delegates who convened on December 3, 1867 to draft a new state constitution. This constitution contained two contentious articles. One called for the disenfranchisement of thousands of voters who were former Confederates and another called for an "iron-clad" oath clause that designated that officials must take an oath that they had not voluntarily borne arms or assisted in any way in the hostility against the United States. The disenfranchising clause would have stricken most moderates and conservatives from the voting lists, and the oath clause would have made it impossible for almost anyone who had assisted the Confederacy to hold office.
James B. Baldwin and Alexander H.H. Stuart led an attack against these restrictive clauses, urging supporters to accept black enfranchisement in exchange for omitting the test-oath. A Committee of Nine presented their case in Washington and President Grant recommended that the constitution be submitted to the people with the objectionable provisions to be voted on separately for approval or rejection. The convention adjourned on April 17, 1868.
The constitution was submitted to the voters on July 6, 1869, and was approved except for the sections relating to test oaths and disenfranchisement, which were voted on separately and defeated. The constitution drafted by the Convention of 1867-1868 for the first time included a provision to allow for universal manhood suffrage. The adopted constitution is sometimes called the Underwood Constitution, named for the president of the convention, John C. Underwood. Voters also elected the Governor, Lieutenant Governor, and various other officials in July 1869. On January 26, 1870, an act of Congress was approved admitting Virginia to the Union, and on the same date the government of the state of Virginia became operative under the new constitution.
Scope and Content
These election records consist of lists of voters by county, magisterial district, and sometimes precinct, who participated in elections held October 22, 1867 (Poll books) and July 6, 1869 (Poll lists), while Virginia was under military rule. The poll books and poll lists both consist of a return of the names of registered voters recorded alphabetically by first letter of the surname (though last names are not generally listed alphabetically within each letter). These records document the first two elections in which African Americans were able to vote.
The 1867 election asked voters to vote for or against a convention to be held to draft a new state constitution and also to elect delegates to the convention if passed. The Poll Books for this election document white and African American voters on separate lists. The records for the 1867 election also include election certificates for each magisterial district that certify the number of votes polled and the results of the election. Several localities also include ballots.
The 1869 election asked voters to decide for or against the newly drafted state constitution, for or against individual clauses in the constitution related to disenfranchisement and test oaths, and to elect the Governor, Lt. Governor, and various other officials. The Poll Lists combine all voters on one document with a column to indicate the race of each voter, though some counties counties/districts ignored these instructions and continued to record white and black voters on separate lists (see Caroline County for example). There are often duplicate poll lists for each district. Most localities also include the ballots cast in the election. A limited number of counties also include Certificates of Registration indicating a change of voting precinct for names stricken from the rolls of one voting precinct after given notice of a permanent change of residence from the district where they were originally registered in 1867; Oath/Affidavits by voters who have relocated swearing that they have not voted in another district and will only vote in one district; and Canvass Returns that document the number of voters polled and the results of the election.
Please note that this collection does not include 1867 and 1869 election records for all localities, as some may have only one or the other, and that the collection does not include election records for the following: Albemarle County, Bath County, Bedford County, Chesterfield County, Dickerson County, Dinwiddie County, Franklin County, Gloucester County, Lunenburg County, New Kent County, Northumberland County, Patrick County, Smyth County, Sussex County, and the cities of Fredericksburg, Lynchburg, and Winchester.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by counties, followed by cities.
Contents List
- Accomack County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Poll books (1st - 3rd Districts), 1867. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Poll books (4th-6th Districts), 1867. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Alexandria County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Poll books (1st - 3rd Districts), 1867. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Poll books (4th - 5th Districts), 1867. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Poll lists (5th District), 1869. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Alleghany County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Poll books and election certificates, 1867. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Amelia County
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Districts), 1867. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Poll books (3rd and 4th Districts), 1867. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Poll books (5th District), 1867. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Poll lists (2nd and 3rd Districts), 1869. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Poll lists (4th District), 1869. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Poll lists (5th District), 1869. (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Amherst County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Poll books (1st District), 1867. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Poll books (2nd District), 1867. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Poll books (3rd District), 1867. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Poll books (4th District), 1867. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Poll books (5th District), 1867. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Poll lists (4th District), 1869. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Poll lists (5th District), 1869. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Appomattox County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Poll books (All Districts), 1867. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Poll lists (1st - 3rd Districts), 1869. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Poll lists (4th and 5th Districts), 1869. (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Augusta County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Election Returns, 1867. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Districts), 1867. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Poll books (3rd and 4th Districts), 1867. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Poll lists (5th and 6th Districts), 1867. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Poll lists (7th - 9th Districts), 1867. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Poll lists (4th and 5th Districts), 1869. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Poll lists (6th and 7th Districts), 1869. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Poll lists (8th and 9th Districts), 1869. (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Bland County
  - Election returns, 1867. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Poll books (All Districts), 1867. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Botetourt County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Election returns, 1867. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Poll books (1st District), 1867. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Poll books (2nd District), 1867. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Poll books (3rd District), 1867. (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Poll books (4th District), 1867. (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Poll books (5th District), 1867. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Ballots, 1866. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Poll lists (4th District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Poll lists (5th District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Brunswick County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Districts), 1867. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Poll books (3rd and 4th Districts), 1867. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Poll books (5th and 6th Districts), 1867. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Poll books (7th District), 1867. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Poll lists (4th District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Poll lists (5th District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Poll lists (6th District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Poll lists (7th District), 1869. (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Buchanan County
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Poll books (All Districts), 1867. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Poll lists (All Districts), 1869. (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Buckingham County
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Poll books (1st District), 1867. (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Poll books (2nd District), 1867. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Poll books (3rd District), 1867. (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Poll books (4th District), 1867. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Poll books (5th District), 1867. (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Poll books (6th District), 1867. (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Poll lists (4th - 6th Districts), 1869. (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Campbell County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Districts), 1867. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Poll books (3rd and 4th Districts), 1867. (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Poll books (5th and 6th Districts), 1867. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Poll books (7th and 8th Districts), 1867. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Poll lists (4th District), 1869. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Poll lists (5th District), 1869. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Poll lists (6th District), 1869. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Poll lists (7th District), 1869. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Poll lists (8th District), 1869. (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Caroline County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Districts), 1867. (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Poll books (3rd - 5th Districts), 1867. (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Poll books (4th District), 1869. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Poll books (5th District), 1869. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Carroll County
  - Election certficiates, 1867. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Poll books (1st - 3rd Districts), 1867. (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Poll books (4th and 5th Districts), 1867. (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Charles City County
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Districts), 1867. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Poll books (3rd and 4th Districts), 1867. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Lists of persons voting upon affidavit, 1869. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Oath of registration, 1869. (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Charlotte County
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Poll lists (4th District), 1869. (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Poll lists (5th District), 1869. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Poll lists (6th District), 1869. (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Clarke County
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Districts), 1867. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Poll books (3rd and 4th Districts), 1867. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Oaths of Residence, 1869. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Craig County
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Poll books (All Districts), 1867. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Culpeper County
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Poll lists (5th and 6th Districts), 1869. (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Cumberland County
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Disticts), 1867. (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Poll books (3rd and 4th Districts), 1867. (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Oaths of residence, 1869. (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Certificates of registration, 1869. (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Poll lists (All Districts), 1869. (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Elizabeth City County
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Poll books (1st District), 1867. (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Poll books (2nd District), 1867. (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Poll books (3rd District), 1867. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Essex County
  - Poll books (1st District), 1867. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Poll books (2nd District), 1867. (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Poll books (3rd District), 1867. (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Poll books (4th District), 1867. (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Poll books (5th District), 1867. (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Poll lists (1st - 3rd Districts), 1869. (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Poll lists (4th and 5th Districts), 1869. (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Fairfax County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Poll books (1st - 3rd Districts), 1867. (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Poll books (4th - 6th Districts), 1867. (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Poll lists (5th and 6th Districts), 1869. (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Fauquier County
  - Poll books and election certificates (1st - 3rd Districts), 1867. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Poll books and election certificates (4th - 6th Districts), 1867. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Poll books and election certificates (7th - 9th Districts), 1867. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Poll lists (5th and 6th Districts), 1869. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Poll lists (7th District), 1869. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Poll lists (8th District), 1869. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Poll lists (9th District), 1869. (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Floyd County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Poll books and election certificates (1st District), 1867. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Poll books and election certificates (2nd District), 1867. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Poll books and election certificates (3rd District), 1867. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Poll books and election records (4th District), 1867. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Poll books and election certificates (5th District), 1867. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Poll lists (5th District), 1869. (Box 12, Folder 19)
- Fluvanna County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Poll books and election certificates (1st - 3rd Districts), 1867. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Poll books and election certificates (4th - 6th Districts), 1867. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Frederick County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Poll books (1st District), 1867. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Poll books (2nd District), 1867. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Poll books (3rd District), 1867. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Poll books (4th District), 1867. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Poll books (5th District), 1867. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Poll books (6th District), 1867. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Poll books (7th District), 1867. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Poll books (8th District), 1867. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Poll lists (5th and 6th Districts), 1869. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Poll lists (7th and 8th Districts), 1869. (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Giles County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Districts), 1867. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Poll books (3rd and 4th Districts), 1867. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Goochland County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Poll books (1st District), 1867. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Poll books (2nd District), 1867. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Poll books (3rd District), 1867. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Poll books (4th District), 1867. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Poll books (5th District), 1867. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Certificates of registration, 1869. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - List of person who voted on affidavits or certifcates, 1869. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Poll lists (3rd - 5th Districts), 1869. (Box 14, Folder 19)
- Grayson County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Poll books (1st - 3rd Districts), 1867. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Poll books (4th - 5th Districts), 1867. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Poll lists (All Districts), 1869. (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Greensville County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Districts), 1867. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Poll books (3rd and 4th Districts), 1867. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Poll lists (3rd and 4th Districts), 1869. (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Halifax County
  - Poll lists (8th District) [only record for this county], 1869. (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Hanover County
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Poll books (1st and 2nd Districts), 1867. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Poll books (3rd and 4th Districts), 1867. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Poll books (5th and 6th Districts), 1867. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Poll lists (4th and 5th Districts), 1869. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Poll lists (6th District), 1869. (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Henrico County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Poll books (1st District), 1867. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Poll books (2nd District), 1867. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Poll books (3rd District), 1867. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Poll books (4th District), 1867. (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Certificates of registration, 1869. (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Oath/Affidavits of residence, 1869. (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Poll lists (1st and 2nd Districts), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Poll lists (4th District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Henry County
  - Poll lists (1st District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Poll lists (4th District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Poll lists (5th District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Poll lists (6th District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Poll lists (7th District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Highland County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Poll books (All Districts), 1867. (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Poll lists (2nd District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Poll lists (3rd District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Poll lists (4th District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Poll lists (5th District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Poll lists (6th District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Poll lists (7th District), 1869. (Box 17, Folder 13)
- Highland County
  - Ballots, 1867. (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Election certificates, 1867. (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Poll books (All Districts), 1867. (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Ballots, 1869. (Box 18, Folder 1)